Soheil Azimi

Phone: +989120929838 | Location: Tehran | age: 28 | Military Service: Guardianship Exemption

<u>LinkedIn: mlsoheyl</u> | <u>GitHub: mlsoheyl</u> | <u>Kaggle: mlsoheyl</u>

azimis@outlook.com | mlsoheyl.github.io

ABOUT

Hi, I have been an M.Sc. student in the field of computer engineering and the subfield of artificial intelligence and robotics at Azad University since 2020. Currently, I'm working on my thesis. Throughout my academic years, I worked for an insurance brokerage company.

I'm very passionate about machine learning and deep learning, especially NLP, so I've been participating in Coursera, Data Camp, and Dayche courses. I worked on machine learning projects and used Python during my classes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Head of the Department of Issuance of Personal Insurance

August 2020 - April 2022

Tamin Ayandeh Insurance Broker, Tehran

My tasks that related to machine learning and data science are listed below:

- Fetching data from different sources
- Preprocessing data
- Evaluation treatment insurance risk
- Create machine learning model to categorize customer risks

Personal Insurance Expert

December 2014 – August 2020

Tamin Ayandeh Insurance Broker, Tehran

EDUCATION

Master's student Degree - Artificial Intelligence and Robotics

September 2020 – Now

Islamic Azad University, Tehran, GPA: 18.42 (working on my thesis)

Bachelor's Degree - Software Engineering

September 2018 - July 2020

Islamic Azad University, Tehran, GPA: 17.68

Associate's Degree - Computer programming

January 2016 – January 2018

Applied Science and Technology, Tehran, GPA: 16.03

HARD SKILLS

Expert in: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Python

Intermediate in: Keras, Transfer Learning, Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Git, Linux, SQL

Basic in: Transformers, Pyspark, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Pycaret, Streamlit, Gradio, Hadoop Ecosystem, MongoDB, Django, Fast API, Docker, Power BI

SOFT SKILLS

Problem Solving, Teamwork, Communication, Creativity

LANGUAGE

Persian (first language), English

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Deep Learning Specialization (130 hours)

Deep Learning Specianzation (150 nours

Coursera

In this course I learned about:

- Sequence Models
- Convolutional Neural Networks
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Machine Learning (20 hours)

August 2022

May 2019

Coursera

Data Science (272 hours)

October 2020 - December 2021

August 2022 - October 2022

Dayche

In this course I learned about:

- Data Mining & Problem-Solving Approach
- Applied Statistics & Probability
- Python Programming & Basic Analytics
- Hacking Skills (Linux & Git)
- Working with Data Sources (SQL & API)
- Fundamentals Of Machine Learning
- Machine Learning Implementation in Python
- Special Topics in Data Science (NLP & Deep Learning)
- Big Data Analytics in Spark

MATLAB Academy

ICDL

Cando

Intermediate Python (4 hours) Data Camp	November 2022
Data Manipulation with Pandas (4 hours) Data Camp	July 2022
Introduction to Data Science in Python (4 hours) Data Camp	July 2022
Introduction To Python (4 hours) Data Camp	July 2022
SQL for Joining Data (5 hours) Data Camp	July 2022
Intermediate to SQL (4 hours) Data Camp	July 2022
MATLAB Onramp	July 2022

PROJECTS

Market Basket Analysis

January 2020

Bachelor Degree Final Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, pandas, matplotlib, mlxtend

In this project, a review was made on association rules discovery methods and implement Apriori algorithm on market basket dataset.

Students Status in Final Examination (Passed or Failed)

June 2020

Practice Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, sklearn

This project is defined as a binary classification. The task was predicting students' status in the final examination (passed or failed). The dataset is available in the UCI machine learning repository. First, define this project as a binary classification problem by summing three scores. After preprocessing the data (get dummies), train the model using the decision tree classifier algorithm. In the inference phase, I achieved 69% accuracy.

Anomaly Detection on Credit Card Dataset (Fraud Detection)

January 2022

Master Degree Advanced Data Mining Course Final Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, scipy, sklearn, keras

Imbalanced classification is the main challenge of this dataset. The dataset includes transactions made on credit cards in September 2013 by European cardholders and was published in Kaggle as a competition. In this project, dimension reduction techniques like PCA and Autoencoder were implemented. In order to extract classification rules, I implemented Decision Tree and Naïve Bayes algorithms, which were evaluated with ROC AUC and achieved 98% and 96%.

RFM Analysis December 2021

Dayche Data Science Class Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, numpy, pandas

The main goal of this project was customer segmentation considered by their loyalty. Calculating Recency, Frequency, Monetary of customer transactions makes this purpose possible.

Predict Apple Stock Price (Time Series)

December 2021

Dayche Data Science Class Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, keras

In this project, predict the open price in the daily timeframe of Apple stocks with LSTM (Long short-term memory). First, with ACF, see autocorrelation to find the best lag time. After that, create a 60-day lag and then model with LSTM. This model can predict the trend of price, but not exactly price.

Personal Blog October 2022

Practice Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, django, HTML, Bootstrap

This is a simple Django project. I create a blog app and define URLs, models, templates, admin page. In this app, you can share a post with the admin page. For a front-end side, I used HTML and Bootstrap.

<u>Linear Regression</u> May 2022

Practice Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, sklearn

I implement linear regression from scratch in three different types (univariate and IID, multivariate and IID, and multivariate and non-IID) using Python and NumPy.

Practice Project

<u>Technologies:</u> python, pandas, streamlit, sklearn

Iris is a well-known machine learning dataset. In this app, I create a web app with Streamlit and predict the type of iris flower.

Cat Classification September 2022

Practice Project (Coursera exercise)

<u>Technologies:</u> python, numpy

Iris is a well-known machine learning dataset. In this app, I create a web app with Streamlit and predict the type of iris flower.

Neural Network May 2022

Practice Project (Coursera exercise)

<u>Technologies:</u> python, numpy

I implement neural network from scratch, including forward and backward propagation, using Python and NumPy.

INTEREST

Tennis, Hiking, Chess, Reading Novel and Books, Travel, Movies